Let's navigate to Resource Groups and find our resource group
Here we are in our resource group. Let's find our Virtual Machine and click on that.
I switched to Visual Studio Code and created a terminal window in the directory of my project.
Now I'm logging into Azure
Now that I've logged into Azure through my Visual Studio Code terminal window, I am going to go back to the portal and start my Virtual Machine
A public IP internet protocal address is allocated and my virtual machine is ready
You can copy the IP address from the portal but let me show you another way to get it from the terminal window.
For this command I am listing all IP addresses for this resource group and virtual machine
Here is the IP address and the allocation method is dynamic because we were cheap and wanted to save money on our project.
Next we are using secure copy to transfer the files from our web app directory to our virtual machine.
Next we will be prompted to login. You may receive a fingerprint prompt, type yes to agree. You may have to type in your password.
After logging in, you will see an exciting display of file transfer.
Let's run the secure shell command to remotely connect to our virtual machine using our username and password.
Let's navigate to our web app directory and list the contents. You can see everything has copied over.
After you're done playing with your Virtual Machine don't forget to go to the portal and stop it.