Let's get started by finding our project and starting our virtual machine
Open a terminal window in visual studio code
and log into Azure with your credentials
Let's copy the public IP address and use it to secure shell into our virtual machine
Make sure you enter your project administration
username and password that we set up in the previous exercise
Our first step is to update the package and repository information
Or next steps is to install nginx which is our webserver and python which will run our web app
Let's now setup the reverse proxy configuration of our nginx webserver so that our client requests can be handled
Let's open a new terminal window and navigate to the sites available directory and take a peek at what's currently there
As you can see the default file looks very similar to our reverse proxy configuration file
Our next step is to unlink this file from nginx as the preferred reverse proxy configuration
Go ahead and open a new terminal window and login to Azure again
Let's use the secure copy command to copy our
reverse proxy configuration file to our home directory on a virtual machine
Let's switch back to our secure shell terminal window and see our file is now in our home directory
Next I'm going to use the sudo command to move my reverse proxy configuration file to the sites
available directory and yes you do need to use sudo because it is an elevated permission area
Let's go there now
As you can see our reverse proxy configuration file is now available in this directory. So let's go ahead and link it.
We are going to link it to the nginx server so it will use that as the preferred proxy configuration.
In order to make all this magic work you do need to restart the ngingx service
Ok let's find our IP address and navigate to our website. It's a bad gateway error!
which is mysterious to many people and I'm going to explain how to fix it
Let's take a look at our proxy file and think about what's going on here. It's a listening and wanting to see something...
Let's give a hint! It might be
in the web app directory.
Our last step is to actually start the web app and to do that we are going to use python. So what we are doing now
is creating the python environment and installing any python dependencies or packages
These package requirements are actually in our web app project if you were to take a look
you would see them listed there and we have to install them.
The last step is to actually run the python application
and if you can see it's now listening on our local host and we refresh our web browser and Voila!
We have a Flask application running on our virtual machine. Congratulations!
Don't forget! After you're done playing with your virtual machine stop it so you don't get charged any more money than you want to