Let's create a Resource
Virtual Machines are found under the Compute category
Make sure you select Virtual Machine and not Virtual Machine Scale Set, and then click Create
Let's walk through the wizard process
Select the Resource Group where to store our resource
Enter a valid virtual machine name
Select the size for the Virtual Machine
It may take a moment for the cost to load
Sort ascending to find the cheapest size
Review the Virtual Machine size for your project needs
Yes, it's true. You can resize the Virtual Machine after creating it.
Select the virtual machine size.
Let's setup our administrator account
Select the password option. Enter a username and a password.
Let's look at the setup wizard for disks.
I don't need any changes here so I am going to look at the Networking tab.
By default, Azure includes settings for a new virtual network.
If you have an existing virtual network, you can add this virtual machine to that network.
Make sure you have the inbound port rules turned on and click the Management tab.
We don't need advanced monitoring so let's disable boot diagnostics.
For this project, let's leave the rest as defaults.
Let's take a look at advanced settings.
For this project, let's leave the defaults.
Click on tags to add custom tags. But's go ahead and Review and Create.
Here you are going to see an estimate of the costs of your virtual machine and some additional terms and conditions to review.
Make sure you carefully review all the settings before you click on the create button.
Let's create the virtual machine and get this project started.
It could take awhile to create a virtual machine. So here is a good idea. Go get a cheeseburger and eat one while you are waiting,
You'll receive a notification that your resource has been created.
Click on Go To Resource
Let's take a look at the overview of our newly created and currently running virtual machine.
Azure created a temporary public IP address for when our virtual mcahine is running.
Click on Stop to stop the virtual machine.
Keep your project cheap and reduce costs. Make sure to stop your virtual machine when you are done working on it.
It will take awhile to stop and the status will change to Deallocating
The final status should say "Stopped Deallocated" and you will now see that your public IP has disappeared.